export const chapter = "Chapter - 10: Electric Current and Its Effects";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question: "What is an electric circuit?",
          optionA: "A device that produces electricity",
          optionB: "A path through which electric current flows",
          optionC: "A type of battery",
          correctAnswer: "B",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the source of electricity in an electric circuit?",
          optionA: "Bulb",
          optionB: "Cell or Battery",
          optionC: "Connecting Wires",
          correctAnswer: "B",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the purpose of a switch in an electric circuit?",
          optionA: "To generate electricity",
          optionB: "To control the flow of electric current",
          optionC: "To connect wires",
          correctAnswer: "B",
        },
        {
          question: "What happens in a closed circuit?",
          optionA: "The electric current flows smoothly",
          optionB: "The circuit is incomplete",
          optionC: "The switch is turned off",
          correctAnswer: "A",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the heating effect of electric current?",
          optionA: "Production of light",
          optionB: "Production of heat when current passes through a wire",
          optionC: "Deflection of a magnetic compass",
          correctAnswer: "B",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which safety device is used to protect household devices from overheating due to high current?",
          optionA: "Electric Iron",
          optionB: "Bulb",
          optionC: "Fuse",
          correctAnswer: "C",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is the advantage of MCBs (Miniature Circuit Breakers) over fuses?",
          optionA: "MCBs are cheaper",
          optionB: "Fuses can't be manually reset",
          optionC: "MCBs can be manually reset without replacing the wire",
          correctAnswer: "C",
        },
        {
          question:
            "How does an electric iron work based on the heating effect of electric current?",
          optionA: "It produces light",
          optionB: "It becomes a magnet",
          optionC: "The coil becomes red hot and gives off heat",
          correctAnswer: "C",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the magnetic effect of electric current?",
          optionA: "Production of heat",
          optionB: "Production of light",
          optionC: "Deflection of a magnetic compass",
          correctAnswer: "C",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is used to remove iron splinters from the eye, based on the magnetic effect of electric current?",
          optionA: "Electromagnet",
          optionB: "Solenoid",
          optionC: "Fuse",
          correctAnswer: "A",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question:
            "An electric circuit is a path through which an ____________ flows.",
          optionA: "Water",
          optionB: "Electric current",
          optionC: "Air",
          correctAnswer: "Electric current",
        },
        {
          question: "A cell converts chemical energy into ____________ energy.",
          optionA: "Mechanical",
          optionB: "Thermal",
          optionC: "Electrical",
          correctAnswer: "Electrical",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Connecting wires in an electric circuit are usually made of copper coated with ____________.",
          optionA: "Rubber",
          optionB: "Plastic",
          optionC: "Glass",
          correctAnswer: "Plastic",
        },
        {
          question:
            "In a closed circuit, the electric current flows from the positive terminal of the cell to the ____________ terminal of the cell.",
          optionA: "Neutral",
          optionB: "Positive",
          optionC: "Negative",
          correctAnswer: "Negative",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The production of heat when an electric current is passed through a wire is known as the ____________ effect.",
          optionA: "Magnetic",
          optionB: "Heating",
          optionC: "Chemical",
          correctAnswer: "Heating",
        },
        {
          question:
            "A safety device used in household circuits to protect devices from high currents is called a ____________.",
          optionA: "Electric Iron",
          optionB: "Switch",
          optionC: "Fuse",
          correctAnswer: "Fuse",
        },
        {
          question:
            "MCBs (Miniature Circuit Breakers) can be manually reset without replacing the ____________.",
          optionA: "Wire",
          optionB: "Bulb",
          optionC: "Switch",
          correctAnswer: "Wire",
        },
        {
          question:
            "An electric iron contains a coil of wire called ____________.",
          optionA: "Filament",
          optionB: "Element",
          optionC: "Conductor",
          correctAnswer: "Element",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The magnetic effect of electric current was discovered by ____________.",
          optionA: "Thomas Edison",
          optionB: "Nikola Tesla",
          optionC: "Hans Christian Oersted",
          correctAnswer: "Hans Christian Oersted",
        },
        {
          question:
            "When an electric current is passed through a coil of wire, and it behaves like a magnet, it is called an ____________.",
          optionA: "Insulator",
          optionB: "Electromagnet",
          optionC: "Solenoid",
          correctAnswer: "Electromagnet",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question:
            "After independence, India's urban spaces no longer show colonial influence.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Urbanization occurs when a town comes into being and prominence due to various causes.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question: "De-urbanization only occurs due to political reasons.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Surat regained its importance primarily due to the trade in silk.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Hill Stations were established during the colonial period as a response to extreme cold climates in India.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Local self-government in municipalities was introduced by Lord Ripon.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Municipalities in towns are primarily funded by the central government.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The Public Works Department (PWD) is responsible for the operation of various facilities like schools and parks.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question: "The first railway line was laid down in India in 1902.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The police organization in colonial India was known for its popularity and integrity among the common people.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
